你知道再过四个星期我们就要结婚了吗
Do you realize that four weeks from today we're getting married?
四个星期  宝贝  四个星期
Four weeks, baby. Four weeks!
你知道每星期你都叫得更大声吗
Do you realize that you get louder each week?
还有这么多事要做
There's still so much to do!
你写好你的婚誓了吗
Have you written your vows yet?
我会去买那种"派得  我要买婚誓"
I figured I'd just buy those. "Pat, I'd like to buy a vow."
亲爱的  要知道一说到婚礼的事
Sweetie, you know I've no sense of humor
我是没有心情开玩笑的
when it comes to the wedding.
好吧  你写好了吗
Right. So have you written yours yet?
没有  但我知道自己要说什么
No, but I know exactly what I'm gonna say.
你会不会刚好知道我要说什么
Do you happen to know exactly what I'm gonna say?
咱们现在就写  没那么难
Let's do it now. It won't be hard.
就写自己的心里话
Say what's in your heart.
看她写得多快  她一定爱我比我爱她更多
Look at her go. She must love me more than I love her!
我有什么问题  别打开那扇回忆之门
What's wrong with me? Don't open that door.
"莫妮卡  没有语言..."
"Monica, there are no words..."
根本就是哑口无言  不该这么费劲啊
There are no words! This shouldn't be this hard!
你之前写过这个  罗斯
You've done this before, Ross.
你的婚誓里说了些什么
What did you say when you made up your vows?
对卡罗尔  我答应她直到我死
With Carol, I promised never to love another woman
不会再爱另一个女人
until the day I die.
她却没这样答应我
She made no such promise.
我真悲哀  莫妮卡就知道要讲什么
I'm so pathetic. Monica knows what she wants to say.
看她奋笔疾书的样子  不停地写呀写
You should have seen her writing and writing and writing.
莫妮卡  什么紧急大事
Monica, what? What's the emergency?
帮我个忙
You have to help me.
我本应写我的婚誓  可却只搞出这个
I'm supposed to write my vows and all I have is this.
我喜欢你穿婚纱的卡通模样
I like the pretty little drawing of you in the wedding dress.
不过你的胸部看来有点小
Except your breasts look kind of small.
那是我的眼睛
Those are my eyes!
-那是我的胸部  -好吧
- Those are my breasts. - Oh, yeah, okay.
何不从简单的开始  像是
Why don't you just start with something simple, like:
"莫妮卡
"Monica,
第一次见到你  我就知道我爱你"
from the moment I met you, I knew I loved you."
这貌似不是实话
I'm not sure I can do that.
各位  这是钱德勒
Everyone, this is Chandler.
我是罗斯的小妹
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister.
好吧
Okay.
好  你可以这样开头
Okay, okay. Maybe you could start with:
钱德勒  即使在我们还是朋友的时候
"Chandler, even though we were friends...
我都一直知道自己想跟你更进一步
...there was a part of me that always knew I wanted more."
好吧  经过一场核武器战争
All right, there's a nuclear holocaust.
我是地球上最后一个男人
I'm the last man on earth.
你会和我约会吗
Would you go out with me?
好吧
Yeah.
婚誓里可以说谎吗
Are we allowed to lie in the vows?
你可以不谈自己以前的感受
Maybe you don't talk about your feelings back then.
你可以谈谈
Maybe you just say something about
他教会你的事情  像是...
all the things that he's taught you, like...
或是你教会他的事
Or all the things you taught him.
大家都知道基本的性感带
Everybody knows the basic erogenous zones.
有1  2  3...
You got one, two, three...
4  5...
...four, five...
6和7
...six and seven.
有7个
There are seven?
-那也算吗  -还蛮重要的
- That's one? - Kind of an important one.
我是倒着看的  没认出来
I was looking at it upside down.
有时候这里也有帮助
Well, you know, sometimes that helps.
好  现在  由1开始...
Okay, now, start out with a little one...
一个2  一个1  2  3...
...a two, a one-two-three...
一个3  一个5...
...a three, a five...
一个4  一个3  2
...a four, a three-two...
2  4  7...
...two, four-seven...
5  7  6  7...
...five-seven, six-seven...
7  7...
...seven, seven...
7...
...seven!
我知道了  这样如何
I got it! How about saying something like:
-莫妮卡  -莫妮卡
- "Monica, - Monica.
回顾我们在一起的时光
when I look back over our time together..."
-然后呢  -剩下你自己来想啊
- Yeah? - I can't do everything.
回顾你们在一起的时光嘛
Look back over your time together.
看  双胞胎
Oh, look, twins!
不公平  我连一个都没有
No fair! I don't even have one,
为什么他们有两个
how come they get two?
-你会有孩子的  -什么时候
- You'll get one. - Yeah, when?
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
我们四十岁的时候  如果都还没结婚
When we're 40, if neither of us are married,
我们俩来生一个如何
what do you say you and I get together and have one?
我为什么会到40岁还没结婚
Why wouldn't I be married when I'm 40?
不  我是说假设
Oh, no. No, I just meant hypothetically.
即使是假设  我为什么会到40岁还没结婚
Hypothetically, why won't I be married when I'm 40?
-不是 -为什么
- No, no. - What is it?
说真的  我身上有什么不适合结婚的特质吗
Seriously, is there something fundamentally un-marriable about me?
怎么样
Well?
我的老天  这个降落伞竟然是个背包
Dear God, this parachute is a knapsack!
今天我要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
他知道我在这儿吗
Do you think he knew I was here?
算你尽力
Nice try.
等一下  等一下
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
莫妮卡...
Look, Monica...
-没有用的  -我保证这样有用
- This is not gonna work. - I bet this will work.
你真棒  我爱你
You are so great! I love you.
什么
What?
没事  我说你真棒  然后就没说话了
Nothing! I said, you're so great, and then I just stopped talking.
-你说你爱我  真不敢相信  -我没说
- You said you love me! I can't believe this. - No, I didn't.
-你说了  -我没说
- Yes, you did. - No, I didn't!
-你爱我  -我不爱
- You love me! - No, I don't!
住嘴  住嘴  住嘴
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
我在想  如果我在这里拆包行李呢
You know, I was thinking, what if I unpack here?
那你的东西都会放在这里
Then all your stuff would be here.
那...
Well...
如果我的东西都在这里的话呢
What if all my stuff was here?
那你就会一直来来往往的
Then you'd be going back and forth all the time.
没什么意义
Doesn't make any sense.
好
Okay.
如果我们住在一起呢  你明白我在说什么吗
What if we live together, and you understand what I'm saying?
你希望这是一个惊喜
You wanted it to be a surprise.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
钱德勒
Chandler...
我这一生...
...in all my life...
从没想过会如此幸运...
...I never thought I would be so lucky...
能爱上我最好的...
...as to fall in love with my best...
我最好的...
My best...
女生不求婚是有原因的
There's a reason why girls don't do this!
好  好  我来
Okay, okay, okay! I'll do it.
我以为...
I thought...
我做得到
I can do this.
我以为...
I thought...
我说什么内容  在哪里求婚很重要
...that it mattered what I said or where I said it.
但我发现唯一重要的是你...
Then I realized the only thing that matters is that you...
和你在一起的日子
You make me happier
我感受到前所未有的幸福
than I ever thought I could be.
如果你愿意...
And if you let me...
我要用这一生的时间来给你同样的幸福感受
I'll spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
莫妮卡
Monica?
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes.
我们可以进来了吗  我们要急死了
Can we come in yet? We're dying out here!
进来  进来
Come in! Come in!
-我们订婚了  -太棒了
- We're engaged! - Yes!
你们在干嘛
What have you guys been up to?
帮钱德勒写他的婚誓  但被他踢出来了...
We were helping Chandler write his vows, but he kicked us out...
因为乔伊一直提不恰当的建议
...because Joey kept making inappropriate suggestions.
"莫妮卡  我爱你的美臀"有什么不恰当
How is "Monica, I love your sweet ass" inappropriate?
莫妮卡写得怎么样
How's Monica coming along with her vows?
这样说吧  幸好她还有美臀
Let's say it's lucky she's got a sweet ass
因为她不太擅长写这个
because she's not so good at the writing.
真不敢相信再过四个星期他们就要结婚了
I can't believe in four weeks they're gonna be married!
希望他们的婚姻美满
Let's just hope it works.
十对夫妇有九对以离婚收场
Nine out of 10 marriages end in divorce.
菲比  没有的事
Phoebe, that's not true.
是啊  你说得对  你的太太们好吗
Yeah, you're right. How's the missus?
真不能相信他们在一起三年了
I can't believe they've been together 3 years.
那么久了吗
Has it been that long?
感觉没那么久  因为他们瞒了我们很久
Maybe it seems like less because they hid it from us for so long.
是我  进来了
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
我今天辛苦了一整天
I've had a very long, hard day.
我要去买炸鸡  你要不要
I'm gonna get some chicken. You want some?
不用  谢了  不要炸鸡  再见
No, thanks. No, chicken. Bye, then.
你还好吧  实在抱歉  他不肯走
Are you okay? I'm so sorry. He wouldn't leave.
一直问我要不要炸鸡
He kept asking if I wanted chicken.
炸鸡
Chicken?
我可以吃点炸鸡
I could eat some chicken.
乔伊
Hey, Joe!
我想要三块鸡  沙拉  豆子  还有可乐
Can I get a three-piece, some coleslaw and some beans and a Coke?
健怡可乐
Diet Coke.
我不知道他们为什么不告诉我们
I don't know why they didn't just tell us.
好像我们会很不淡定似的
I know. It's not like we weren't cool about it.
你  和你
You? And you?
你不能说  没有人知道
Yes, but you cannot tell. No one knows.
怎么发生的  何时发生的
How? When?
-在伦敦发生的  -在伦敦
- It happened in London. - In London?!
我们没告诉任何人
The reason we didn't tell anyone was
不希望把事情搞大
because we didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
可这就是大事
But it is a big deal!
-我一定要告诉别人  -不要
- I have to tell someone. - No, no!
-不要  -拜托
- You can't. - Please, please!
我们不想面对大家的反应
We don't want to deal with telling everyone, okay?
答应我你不会说
Just promise you won't tell.
好吧
All right!
我等不及要和你在一起了
I can't wait to be with you.
我告诉瑞秋我要洗几个小时的衣服
I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry for a couple of hours.
洗衣服  那是我的新匿称吗
Laundry? Is that my new nickname?
你知道你的匿称是什么  大...
You know what your nickname is, Mr. Big...
看  是莫妮卡和钱德勒
Oh, look, there's Monica and Chandler.
嘿  你们两个
Hey, you guys! Hey!
钱德勒和莫妮卡  钱德勒和莫妮卡
Chandler and Monica! Chandler and Monica!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
-钱德勒和莫妮卡  -我的天啊
- Chandler and Monica! - Oh, my God!
-我的眼睛  我的眼睛  -菲比  菲比
- Oh, my eyes! My eyes! - Phoebe! Phoebe!
-没事的  没事的  -不  他们在做爱
- It's okay! It's okay! - No! They're doing it!
我知道  我知道
I know! I know! I know!
-你知道  -对  我知道
- You know? - Yes, I know!
乔伊也知道  但罗斯不知道
And Joey knows, but Ross doesn't know,
你不能再喊了
so you have to stop screaming!
出什么事了
Hey, what's going on?
怎么了
What? What?
没什么  天啊  我们好兴奋
Nothing. Oh, God! We're just so excited
你可能会搬过来
that you might get this apartment!
-事实上  看起来不错  -看来很不错
- Actually, it looks really good. - It looks pretty good!
过来啊  快点
Get in here! Come on!
他们知道你知道  但他们不知道瑞秋知道
So they know you know, and they don't know that Rachel knows?
对  但你知道吗  谁知道什么并不重要
Yes, but you know what? It doesn't matter who knows what.
现在有足够的人知道了
Now enough of us know,
就可以告诉他们我们知道了
that we can just tell them we know.
谎言和秘密终于可以终结了
Now all the lying and the secrets will finally be over.
或者我们不要告诉他们我们知道
Or we could not tell them we know
我们可以找点小乐子
and have a little fun of our own.
好  该走了  不然电影要迟到了
All right, we better go if we're gonna catch that movie.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
再见  钱德勒  我已经开始想你了
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
你看到了吗  她很不正经地捏了我一下
Did you see that? With the inappropriate and the pinching?
我看到了
Actually, I did.
你现在相信她喜欢上我了吧
So now do you believe that she's attracted to me?
天啊  天啊  她知道我们的事了
Oh, my God! Oh, my God, she knows about us!
-菲比知道我们的事  -我没告诉她们
- Phoebe knows about us! - Well, I didn't tell them.
她们  她们是谁
Them? Who's them?
菲比和乔伊
Phoebe and Joey.
乔伊
Joey!
还有瑞秋
And Rachel.
我本来要告诉你们的 可是她们要我答应不说
I would've told you, but they made me promise not to tell.
她们以为他们很厉害  竟然玩我们
Oh, man. They think they are so slick, messing with us!
可是  他们不知道我们已经知道他们知道
But, see, they don't know that we know that they know.
-所以...-对
- So... - Ah, yes!
整人的变成被整的
The messers become the messees!
天啊  他要我过去
Oh, my God, he wants me to come over
摸他的二头肌什么的
and feel his bicep and more!
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
真不敢相信他会对莫妮卡这样...
I can't believe he'd do that to Mo...
乔伊  他们知道我们知道了吗
Joey? Do they know that we know?
-不知道  -乔伊
- No. - Joey!
-他们知道你们知道了  -我就知道
- They know you know. - I knew it!
这两个人太过分了
I cannot believe those two!
他们以为可以耍我们
They thought that they could mess with us?
他们想要耍我们
They're trying to mess with us?
他们不知道我们知道他们知道我们知道
They don't know that we know they know we know.
乔伊  你什么也不能说
Joey, you can't say anything.
即使我想说也不知道要怎么说
Couldn't if I wanted to.
局面完全失控了
This is getting out of hand!
她要我替她抹乳液
She wants me to put lotion on her!
她那是虚张声势
She's bluffing!
她没有退缩  她快要扑上来了
She's not backing down. She went like this:
他没有退缩  他去拿乳液了
He's not backing down. He went to get lotion.
你们还没玩完吗
Oh, man. Aren't you guys done yet?
菲比早点攻破钱德勒
Joey, just look at it this way. The sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler,
这件事就早一点完全公开
the sooner this is all over and in the open.
-我喜欢  -好
- I like that. - Okay.
好  给他看你的内衣
Okay, show him your bra.
他最怕内衣了  他不会解内衣
He's afraid of bras. Can't work them.
哇  你没扯掉任何一个扣子
Wow! You didn't rip off any buttons.
这又不是第一次了
It's not my first time.
你回去  勾引她  直到把她击溃
You go back out there and seduce her till she cracks.
好  给我一秒钟
Okay, give me a second.
-你把这里打扫过了  -当然
- Did you clean up in here? - Of course.
你要走了吗
Oh, you're going?
除非你跟我一起走  爱人
Not without you, lover.
这是我的内衣
So this is my bra.
非常非常好看
It's very, very nice.
过来
Well, come here.
我们就要上床了  我好开心
I'm very happy we're gonna have all the sex.
你应该开心  我的柔软度很好
You should be. I'm very bendy.
-我现在要吻你了  -如果我没先吻你的话
- I'm gonna kiss you now. - Not if I kiss you first.
我们现在除了接吻  没有别的事可做了
I guess there's nothing left for us to do but kiss.
来了
Here it comes.
我们的初吻
Our first kiss.
-好好好  你赢了  -哈
- Okay, okay, okay, fine, you win! - Ha!
-我不能和你上床  -为什么不能
- I can't have sex with you. - Why not?
-因为我爱莫妮卡  -你怎么了
- Because I'm in love with Monica. - You're what?
爱她  对  我爱她  我爱她
Love her! That's right, I love her! I love her!
我爱你  莫妮卡
I love you, Monica.
我也爱你  钱德勒
I love you too, Chandler.
我以为你们两个只是炮友
I thought you guys were doing it.
没想到你们相爱了
I didn't know you were in love.
就是这样  结束了  大家都知道了
So that's it, it's over. Everybody knows.
其实  罗斯还不知道
Well, actually, Ross doesn't.
请大家还不要告诉他
No, we'd appreciate if no one told him yet.
不是吧
No.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
放开我妹妹
Get off my sister!
朋友要结婚了  很多事都会改变
You know, your friends getting married, it's gotta change things.
变化真的会那么大吗
You really think it'll be that different?
怎么能不变呢  他们很快会有小孩...
How could it not be? Pretty soon, they're gonna have kids...
会和其他有孩子的夫妇
...and then they're just gonan be hanging out
待在一起
with other couples who have kids.
也许他们会搬离纽约
And then maybe they're gonna have to leave the city...
到某个靠近沃尔沃经销商的地方
...to be near a Volvo dealership.
万事皆无常
Things change.
我不要他们搬到沃尔沃经销商附近去住
But I don't want them to move to a Volvo dealership.
乔伊  会没事的
It'll be okay, Joe.
抱歉  我只是...我希望能像以前一样
Sorry. I just... I like things the way they are.
这个光着身子的小孩是谁
Who's this little naked guy?
这个光着身子的小孩是我
That little naked guy would be me.
你看看这个小东西
Look at the little thing.
是啊
Yes.
对  那是我的小鸡鸡
Yes, fine, that is my penis.
我们现在可以成熟点了吗
Can we be grownups now?
-这都是谁  -问倒我了
- Who are those people? - Got me.
正中间的是奶奶
That's Nana right there in the middle.
-哇  -我看看
- Wow. - Let's see.
我和一帮朋友在爪哇乔店里
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
莫妮卡  你很像你祖母  那时她几岁
Monica, you look like your grandmother. How old was she there?
我看看  1939年
Let's see, 1939.
对  24  25岁
Yeah, 24, 25.
看来是很快乐的一帮朋友
Looks like a fun gang.
看看看  我找到莫妮卡光着身子的照片了
Look, look, look! I got Monica naked.
我看
Let me see.
不  这还是我
No, that would be me again.
-嘿  大伙儿  -怎么样啊
- Hey, you guys. - What's going on?
我们刚刚提到...
Well, we were just talking about...
你们要结婚了  非常地棒
...you guys getting married and how great it is.
对  你们可以买一辆沃尔沃
Yeah, you can get a Volvo.
如果你们真想那样的话
If that's what you really want.
你们真好
That's so sweet.
-我们都写完婚誓了  -我们可以看吗
- So we both finished our vows. - Can we read them?
只要我不看到钱德勒的  他不看到我的就好
Just as long as I don't hear Chandler's and he doesn't hear mine.
-好  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
好感人
Oh, that's beautiful.
好好笑  很好
Funny one! That's good!
莫妮卡  你嫁给我好吗
Monica, will you marry me?
什么  我没看懂
What? I don't get it.
是哟
Oh, yeah!
-这太爆笑了  -钱德勒
- Man, this is hilarious! - Chandler!
亲爱的  别担心  我们可以让你的更好笑
Don't worry, honey. We'll make yours funnier.
你们觉得如何
Okay, what do you guys think?
-老兄  -我从没见过这么伟大的爱情
- Dude... - I have never known love like this.
-你真的喜欢吗  -老兄
- You really like it? - Dude!
你怎么写出来的
How did you write this?
我偷了莫妮卡的改成我的名字
I stole Monica's and changed the name.
-你不能这么做  -如果他先讲的话就可以
- You can't do that! - If he goes first, he can!